Anyone is an enemy for a price.
Ronin is a action, thriller, crime film directed by John Frankenheimer.
A briefcase with undisclosed contents – sought by Irish terrorists and
the Russian mob – makes its way into criminals' hands.
An Irish liaison assembles a squad of mercenaries, or 'ronin', and
gives them the thorny task of recovering the case.
Sam, played by Robert De Niro.
Vincent, played by Jean Reno.
Deirdre, played by Natascha McElhone.
Gregor, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Larry, played by Skipp Sudduth.
Seamus O'Rourke, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Ronin is a 1998 American  neo-noir action thriller film directed by John Frankenheimer and written
by John David Zeik and David Mamet, the latter under the pseudonym Richard Weisz.
It stars an ensemble cast consisting of Robert De Niro, Jean Reno, Natascha
McElhone, Stellan Skarsgård, Sean Bean and Jonathan Pryce.
The film is about a team of former special operatives who are hired to steal a mysterious,
heavily guarded briefcase while navigating a maze of shifting loyalties.
The film was praised for its realistic car chases in Nice and Paris.
Frankenheimer signed to direct Zeik's screenplay, which Mamet rewrote in
1997 to expand De Niro's role and develop plot details.
The film was photographed by Robert Fraisse in his native
France from November 3, 1997, to March 3, 1998.
Professional racing car drivers coordinated and performed the vehicle stunts,
and Elia Cmiral scored the film, his first for a major studio.
Ronin premiered at the 1998 Venice Film Festival before
its general release on September 25.
Critics were generally positive about the film's action, casting and
technical aspects, while the plot attracted criticism.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing
$70.7 million on a $55 million budget.
Ronin, Frankenheimer's last well-received feature film, was
considered to be a return to form for the director.
Film critic and historian Stephen Prince called the film
Frankenheimer's "end-of-career masterpiece".
The car chases, which were favorably compared with those in Bullitt and The French Connection,
were included on several media outlets' lists as among the best depicted on film.
The film explores themes of france, paris, france,
arms deal, mercenary, suitcase.
The tone is intense.